[
  {
    "question": "Find the sum of all integer bases $b>9$ for which $17_b$ is a divisor of $97_b.$.\\n\\n Answer: We are tasked with finding the number of bases b > 9 such that $\\frac{9b+7}{b+7} \\in Z$. Notice that $\\frac{9b+7}{b+7} = \\frac{9b+63-49}{b+7} = \\frac{9(b+7)-49}{b+7} = 9 - \\frac{49}{b+7}$ ",
    "answer": "70"
  },
  {
    "question": "On $\\triangle ABC$ points $A, D, E$, and $B$ lie in that order on side $\\overline{AB}$ with $AD = 4$, $DE = 16$, $EB = 8$. Points $A, F, G$ and $C$ lie in that order on side $\\overline{AC}$ with $AF = 13$, $FG = 52$, and $GC = 26$. Let $M$ be the reflection of $D$ through $F$, and let $N$ be the reflection of $G$ through $E$. Quadrilateral $DEGF$ has area $288$. Find the area of heptagon $AFNBCEM$.\\n\\n Answer: Note that the triangles outside of \\triangle ABC have the same height as the unshaded triangles in \\triangle ABC. Because of these reflections, and the same bases, we conclude that |AFNBCEM| = |ABC|. Through the given lengths of 4 - 16 - 8 on the left and 13 - 52 - 26 on the right, we conclude the lines through \\triangle ABC are parallel and the sides are in a 1:8:2 ratio.",
    "answer": "588"
  },
  {
    "question": "The 9 members of a baseball team went to an ice-cream parlor after their game. Each player had a singlescoop cone of chocolate, vanilla, or strawberry ice cream. At least one player chose each flavor, and the number of players who chose chocolate was greater than the number of players who chose vanilla, which was greater than the number of players who chose strawberry. Let $N$ be the number of different assignments of flavors to players that meet these conditions. Find the remainder when $N$ is divided by $1000.$\\n\\n Answer: We start by finding the only 3 possible cases since C > V >S. We arrive at (2,3,4), (1,2,6), (1,3,5) which lead to respectively:  (2,3,4) = \\binom{9}{2,3,4} = \\frac{9*8*7*6*5*4!}{5!*4!*3!} = 1260, (1,3,5) = ",
    "answer": "16"
  },
  {
    "question": "Find the number of ordered pairs $(x,y)$, where both $x$ and $y$ are integers between $-100$ and $100$, inclusive, such that $12x^2-xy-6y^2=0$.\\n\\n Answer: you can use the quadratic formula for this equation $12x^2 - xy - 6y^2 = 0$, the formula: \\frac{b\\pm (b^2-4ac)^{0.5}}{2a} = \\frac{-xy \\pm (x^2y^2+(12*6*4*x^2*y^2)^{0.5}}{24x^2}",
    "answer": "117"
  },
  {
    "question": "There are $8!= 40320$ eight-digit positive integers that use each of the digits 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8 exactly once. Let N be the number of these integers that are divisible by $22$. Find the difference between $N$ and 2025.\\n\\n Answer: Notice that if the 8-digit number is divisible by 22, it must have an even units digit. Therefore, by the cases, the last digit be either 2,4,6,8. Due to symmetry, upon finding the total count of one of these last digit cases (we look at last digit $2$ here), we may multiply the resulting value by $4$ Now we just need to find the number of positions of the remaining numbers such that the units digit is $2$ and the number is divisible by $11$. Denote the odd numbered positions to be $a_1, a_3, a_5, a_7$ and the even numbered positions to be $a_2, a_4, a_6$ (recall $a_8=2$). By the divisibility rule of $11$, we must have: \\[(a_1 - a_3 - a_5 - a_7) - (a_2 + a_4 + a_6 + 2)\\] which must be congruent to 0 (mod 11)..",
    "answer": "279"
  },
  {
    "question": "An isosceles trapezoid has an inscribed circle tangent to each of its four sides. The radius of the circle is $3$, and the area of the trapezoid is $72$. Let the parallel sides of the trapezoid have lengths $r$ and $s$, with $r \\neq s$. Find $r^2+s^2$ \\n\\n Answer: To begin with, because of tangents from the circle to the bases, the height is $2\\cdot3=6.$ The formula for the area of a trapezoid is $\\frac{h(b_1+b_2)}{2}.$ Plugging in our known values we have \\[\\frac{6(r+s)}{2}=72.\\]\\[r+s=32.\\]Next, we use Pitot's Theorem which states for tangential quadrilaterals $AB+CD=AD+BC.$ Since we are given $ABCD$ is an isosceles trapezoid we have $AD=BC=x.$ Using Pitot's we find,\\[AB+CD=r+s=2x=32.\\]\\[x=16.\\]Finally we can use the Pythagorean Theorem by dropping an altitude from D,",
    "answer": "504"
  },
  {
    "question": "The twelve letters $A$,$B$,$C$,$D$,$E$,$F$,$G$,$H$,$I$,$J$,$K$, and $L$ are randomly grouped into six pairs of letters. The two letters in each pair are placed next to each other in alphabetical order to form six two-letter words, and then those six words are listed alphabetically. For example, a possible result is $AB$, $CJ$, $DG$, $EK$, $FL$, $HI$. The probability that the last word listed contains $G$ is $\\frac mn$, where $m$ and $n$ are relatively prime positive integers. Find $m+n$. \\n\\n Answer: Note that order does not matter here. This is because any permutation of the $6$ pairs will automatically get ordered in alphabetical order. The same is true for within each of the pairs. In other words, AB CH DI EJ FK GL should be counted equally as HC AB DI EJ FK GL. We construct two cases: $G$ is the first letter of the last word and $G$ is the second letter of the last word. Our first case is when $G$ is the first letter of the last word. Then the second letter of the last word must be one of $H, I, J, K, L$. Call that set of $4$ letters $\\Omega$. There are $4$ ways to choose the second letter from $\\Omega$. The other $3$ letters of $\\Omega$ must be used in the other $4$ words.",
    "answer": "821"
  },
  {
    "question": "Let $k$ be a real number such that the system\\begin{align*} |25+20i-z|&=5\\\\ |z-4-k|&=|z-3i-k| \\\\ \\end{align*}has exactly one complex solution $z$. The sum of all possible values of $k$ can be written as $\\frac{m}{n},$ where $m$ and $n$ are relatively prime positive integers. Find $m+n.$ Here $i=\\sqrt{-1}.$ \\n \\n Answer: The complex number $z$ must satisfy the following conditions on the complex plane: $1.$ The magnitude between $z$ and $(25,15)$ is $5.$ This can be represented by drawing a circle with center $(25,15)$ and radius $5.$ $2.$ It is equidistant from the points $(4+k,0)$ and $(k,3).$ Hence it must lie on the perpendicular bisector of the line connecting these points.",
    "answer": "77"
  },
  {
    "question": "The parabola with equation $y = x^2 - 4$ is rotated $60^\\circ$ counterclockwise around the origin. The unique point in the fourth quadrant where the original parabola and its image intersect has $y$-coordinate $\\frac{a - \\sqrt{b}}{c}$, where $a$, $b$, and $c$ are positive integers, and $a$ and $c$ are relatively prime. Find $a + b + c$. \\n \\n Answer: To begin with notice, a $45^{\\circ}$ rotation counterclockwise about the origin on the $y-$axis is the same as a reflection over the line $y=-x\\sqrt{3}.$",
    "answer": "62"
  },
  {
    "question": "The $27$ cells of a $3 \\times 9$ grid are filled in using the numbers $1$ through $9$ so that each row contains $9$ different numbers, and each of the three $3 \\times 3$ blocks heavily outlined in the example below contains $9$ different numbers, as in the first three rows of a Sudoku puzzle.\\[\\begin{array}{|c|c|c||c|c|c||c|c|c|}\\hline 4 & 2 & 8 & 9 & 6 & 3 & 1 & 7 & 5 \\\\\\hline 3 & 7 & 9 & 5 & 2 & 1 & 6 & 8 & 4 \\\\\\hline 5 & 6 & 1 & 8 & 4 & 7 & 9 & 2 & 3 \\\\\\hline\\end{array}\\]The number of different ways to fill such a grid can be written as $p^a \\cdot q^b \\cdot r^c \\cdot s^d$ where $p$, $q$, $r$, and $s$ are distinct prime numbers and $a$, $b$, $c$, $d$ are positive integers. Find $p \\cdot a + q \\cdot b + r \\cdot c + s \\cdot d$. \\n \\n Answer: We will fill out the grid row by row. Note that there are $9!=2^7\\cdot 3^4\\cdot 5\\cdot 7$ ways to fill out the first row. For the second row, we will consider a little casework. WLOG let the first row be $122 | 345 | 789$ (bars indicate between the $3\\times 3$ squares).",
    "answer": "62"
  },
  {
    "question": "A piecewise linear function is defined by\\[f(x) = \\begin{cases} x & \\text{if } x \\in [-1, 1) \\\\ 2 - x & \\text{if } x \\in [1, 3)\\end{cases}\\]and $f(x + 4) = f(x)$ for all real numbers $x.$ The graph of $f(x)$ has the sawtooth pattern depicted below. The parabola $x = 34y^2$ intersects the graph of $f(x)$ at finitely many points. The sum of the $y$-coordinates of these intersection points can be expressed in the form $\\tfrac{a + b\\sqrt c}d,$ where $a, b, c$ and $d$ are positive integers, $a, b,$ and $d$ has greatest common divisor equal to $1,$ and $c$ is not divisible by the square of any prime. Find $a + b + c + d.$ \\n \\n Answer: Note that $f(x)$ consists of lines of the form $y = x - 4k$ and $y = 4k + 2 - x$ for integers $k$. In the first case, we get $33y^{2} = y - 4k$ and the sum of the roots is $\\tfrac{1}{33}$ by Vieta. ",
    "answer": "259"
  },
  {
    "question": "The set of points in $3$-dimensional coordinate space that lie in the plane $x+y+z=75$ whose coordinates satisfy the inequalities $$x-yz<y-zx<z-xy$$ forms three disjoint convex regions. Exactly one of those regions has finite area. The area of this finite region can be expressed in the form $a\\sqrt{b},$ where $a$ and $b$ are positive integers and $b$ is not divisible by the square of any prime. Find $a+b.$ \\n \\n Answer: Rewriting we have $z=75-x-y.$ From the inequality $x-yz<y-zx$ we can rewrite to get,\\[x+y(75-x-y)< y-x(75-x-y).\\]\\[76x+76y+y^2-x^2<0.\\]\\[(x-y+76)(x-y)<0.\\]",
    "answer": "510"
  },
  {
    "question": "Alex divides a disk into four quadrants with two perpendicular diameters intersecting at the center of the disk. He draws $25$ more lines segments through the disk, drawing each segment by selecting two points at random on the perimeter of the disk in different quadrants and connecting those two points. Find the expected number of regions into which these $27$ line segments divide the disk. \\n \\n Answer: First, we calculate the probability that two segments intersect each other. Let the quadrants be numbered $1$ through $4$ in the normal labeling of quadrants, let the two perpendicular diameters be labeled the $x$-axis and $y$-axis, and let the two segments be $A$ and $B.$ $\\textbf{Case 1:}$ Segment $A$ has endpoints in two opposite quadrants. This happens with probability $\\frac{1}{2}.$ WLOG let the two quadrants be $1$ and $2.$ We do cases in which quadrants segment $B$ lies in.",
    "answer": "204"
  },
  {
    "question": "Let $ABCDE$ be a convex pentagon with $AB=14$, $BC=7$, $CD=24$, $DE=13$, $EA=26$, and $\\angle B=\\angle E=60^{\\circ}$. For each point $X$ in the plane, define $f(X)=AX+BX+CX+DX+EX$. The least possible value of $f(X)$ can be expressed as $m+n\\sqrt{p}$, where $m$ and $n$ are positive integers and $p$ is not divisible by the square of any prime. Find $m+n+p$. \\n \\n Answer: Assume $AX=a, BX=b, CX=c$, by Ptolemy inequality we have $a+2b\\leq \\sqrt{3}XE; a+2c\\leq \\sqrt{3}BX$, while the inequality is reached when both $CXAB$ and $AXDE$ are concyclic. ",
    "answer": "60"
  },
  {
    "question": "Let $N$ denote the numbers of ordered triples of positive integers $(a, b, c)$ such that $a, b, c \\le 3^6$ and $a^3 + b^3 + c^3$ is a multiple of $3^7$. Find the remainder when $N$ is divided by $1000$. \\n \\n Answer: We are given that $N = \\#\\{(a,b,c) \\in [1,3^6]^3 : 3^7 \\mid (a^3+b^3+c^3)\\},$ and we wish to compute the remainder when is divided by 999.",
    "answer": "735"
  }
]